<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-04T11:11:50+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the blog! (+ technical explanation)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/Welcome-to-the-blog!-(+-technical-explanation).html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the blog! (+ technical explanation)" /><published>2024-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/Welcome%20to%20the%20blog!%20(+%20technical%20explanation)</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/Welcome-to-the-blog!-(+-technical-explanation).html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, and welcome to the first post of my new website. This has been about a year in the making, and I’m really happy with how it’s turned out. In the future, I’ll be posting all my programming, 3d-printing and othe r miscellaneous techie projects here. More pages are also due to be added in the future, as well as rss and newsletter capabilities.</p>

<h3 id="how-does-the-website-work">How does the website work?</h3>

<p>Well - it’s complicated. I started this project, trying to build a custom, plain HTML + CSS website, with a few python scripts to manage the blogging system - it went about as well as you’d expect, but I learned some valuable web development skills that are used in this final versions of the website. So, finally, I settled on using Jekyll for the backend. For hosting, I used GitHub pages, but using actions, instead of the default configuration. This was to allow me to use the jekyll-paginate-v2 and jekyll-sitemap plugins. My domain registrar is NameCheap, as they had the cheapest rate for this url, and I used CloudFlare free tier for DNS, caching and CDN purposes. Finally, the the aestetics are made using the fantastic <a href="https://jdan.github.io/98.css/">98.css</a> and Alex Meub’s <a href="https://win98icons.alexmeub.com/">Windows 98 Icon collection</a>.</p>

<p>So, expect more posts like this in the future (although, they’ll probably be longer next time) and more features to come.</p>]]></content><author><name>ProbablyIdiot</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, and welcome to the first post of my new website. This has been about a year in the making, and I’m really happy with how it’s turned out. In the future, I’ll be posting all my programming, 3d-printing and othe r miscellaneous techie projects here. More pages are also due to be added in the future, as well as rss and newsletter capabilities.]]></summary></entry></feed>